Get ready for frisky business.
Garfield is a comedy, family film directed by Peter Hewitt.
Garfield, the fat, lazy, lasagna lover, has everything a cat could want.
But when Jon, in an effort to impress the Liz - the vet and an old high-school crush - adopts a
dog named Odie and brings him home, Garfield gets the one thing he doesn't want.
Competition.
Garfield (voice), played by Bill Murray.
Jon, played by Breckin Meyer.
Liz, played by Jennifer Love Hewitt.
Happy Chapman, played by Stephen Tobolowsky.
Wendell, played by Evan Arnold.
Christopher Mello, played by Mark Christopher Lawrence.
Garfield: The Movie (or simply Garfield) is a 2004 American live-action
animated comedy film based on Jim Davis' comic strip Garfield.
Directed by Peter Hewitt and written by Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow, it was produced and distributed by 20th Century Fox with the
co-production of Davis Entertainment Company, and stars Breckin Meyer as Jon Arbuckle, Jennifer Love Hewitt as Dr.
Liz Wilson and features Bill Murray as the voice of Garfield,
who was created with computer-generated imagery.
Garfield: The Movie was released in the United States on June 11, 2004.
Despite receiving negative reviews from critics, the film was a commercial success,
grossing $208.1 million worldwide on a $50 million production budget.
A sequel, Garfield: A Tail of Two Kitties, was released in 2006.
The film is also dedicated to Lorenzo Music, the original
voice of Garfield, who died on August 4, 2001.
The film explores themes of cat, competition,
veterinarian, mascot, based on comic.
The tone is lighthearted.